Wenxing Duan

W.Duan-4@sms.ed.ac.uk | +44 07916114025

209, Block E Gateway Apartment, Edinburgh, United Kingdom, EH75BH

A highly committed prospective graduate with a strong interest in computer programming and extensive programming, math, and robotics competition experience. As a keen fanatic of blockchain technology, cryptocurrency, and finance since 2015, participated in the lido.fi permissionless liquid staking system design. Having grasped the development principles and operating mechanisms of various cryptocurrencies; am able to use the smart contract language Solidity proficiently. Eager to continue to explore the boundless potential of blockchain and decentralization.

EDUCATION

University of Edinburgh, UK

09/2019 - 06/2023

BSc Computer Science

- Selected Courses: Introductory Applied Machine Learning, Compiling Techniques, Computer Communications and Networks, Blockchains and Distributed Ledgers, Computer Security, Introduction to Modern Cryptography, Introduction to Quantum Computing, Quantum Cyber Security
- Stanford University Course CS231n: Convolutional Neural Networks for Visual Recognition

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Nethermind, *Edinburgh, United Kingdom Cryptography & Blockchain Research Intern*

06/2022 - 09/2022

- Participated in the protocol research of the next phase of the Lido project.
- Studied and analysed current mainstream oracle protocols, including DECO, Town Crier, Chainlink, Provable, etc.
- Participated in the research of decentralized identity (Decentralized Identity), and learned and analyzed other feasible solutions for on-chain identity, including CanDID, soulbound token, verifiable credentials, etc.
- Learned the relevant knowledge of zero-knowledge proof and participated in the formulation of the trustless verification framework scheme for the next stage of Lido.
- Wrote a smart contract to measure the performance of ETH2.0 validators using the Provable oracle
- Improved proficiency in Solidity; grasped the most advanced trustless oracle model in the industry, improved understanding of zero-knowledge proofs, and learn about the latest developments in the field of decentralized identity.

Huazhong University of Science and Technology, Wuhan, China

06/2021 - 09/2021

- Summer Research Assistant
- Participated in "China Software Cup" as a member of the Huazhong University of Science and Technology team
- Coordinated the 4-person team in the project "Hazardous Agricultural Pest Recognition System", which earned us National Second Prize
- Studied and researched the academic literature on cutting-edge research into fine-grained recognition with Associate Professor Tang He
- Developed an identification system of harmful agricultural pests based on fine-grained identification
- Responsible for back-end development and machine vision development
- Mastered knowledge of back-end development, improved knowledge of database SQLite, grasped the principles and applications of machine vision
- Utilized Python, TensorFlow, PyTorch, Recurrent Attention Convolutional Neural Network, SQLite

${\bf Shanghai\ Zhuofan\ Technology\ Co.,\ Ltd.,\it Shanghai,\ China}$

06/2020 - 09/2020

- Backend Development Intern
- Participated in the backend service and system maintenance of Xiangyang Municipal Affairs Service Network
- Assisted senior engineers in the development and maintenance of the "Hubei Government Affairs Approval Platform" project
- Assisted in testing a number of new functions including automatic query webpage generation, data transfer.
- Supported senior engineers by processing, analyzing, and cleaning platform data using Python script.
- Participated in testing the database of the Xiangyang government's mobile staff management app "Ehuiban"
- Improved understanding of the production and testing processes of regular software manufacturers an grasped the operating principles of numerous website backgrounds

ACADEMIC AWARDS & HONOURS

•	China Software Cup Second Prize	09/2021
•	Canadian Programming Competition Top 5%	03/2019
•	University of Waterloo Euclid Mathematics Contest Top 5%	03/2019
•	Australian Mathematics Competition First Prize	11/2018
•	National Youth Robot Competition 5th place	09/2015

OTHER SKILLS & INTERESTS

Professional Skills/ Programming Languages: Proficient in Python, Flask, Solidity, C, Java, Haskell, all Microsoft Office suite applications, Premiere, After Effects, Audition, Photoshop

Languages: English (IELTS 6.5), Chinese (native speaker)

Interests: Cryptography/ Blockchain fanatic, machine vision, monitoring financial markets, ZKP, compilers, travel encompassing EU/USA/ Asia, keeping fit